Sentence 0:
===========
.......................................
('Turing', 'PERSON'),('was', 'O'),('born', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('Maida', 'LOCATION'),('Vale', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('London', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('while', 'O'),('his', 'O'),('father', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('Julius', 'PERSON'),('Mathison', 'PERSON'),('Turing', 'PERSON'),('(', 'O'),('1873–1947', 'O'),(')', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('was', 'O'),('on', 'O'),('leave', 'O'),('from', 'O'),('his', 'O'),('position', 'O'),('with', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('Indian', 'ORGANIZATION'),('Civil', 'ORGANIZATION'),('Service', 'ORGANIZATION'),('(', 'O'),('ICS', 'O'),(')', 'O'),('at', 'O'),('Chatrapur', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('then', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('Madras', 'LOCATION'),('Presidency', 'O'),('and', 'O'),('presently', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('Odisha', 'LOCATION'),('state', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('British', 'O'),('India', 'LOCATION'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 1:
===========
Turing's father was the son of a clergyman, the Rev.
.......................................
('Turing', 'PERSON'),("'s", 'O'),('father', 'O'),('was', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('son', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('a', 'O'),('clergyman', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('Rev', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 2:
===========
.......................................
('John', 'PERSON'),('Robert', 'PERSON'),('Turing', 'PERSON'),(',', 'O'),('from', 'O'),('a', 'O'),('Scottish', 'O'),('family', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('merchants', 'O'),('that', 'O'),('had', 'O'),('been', 'O'),('based', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('Netherlands', 'LOCATION'),('and', 'O'),('included', 'O'),('a', 'O'),('baronet', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 3:
===========
Turing's mother, Julius' wife, was Ethel Sara Turing (née Stoney 1881–1976), daughter of Edward Waller Stoney, chief engineer of the Madras Railways.
.......................................
('Turing', 'PERSON'),("'s", 'O'),('mother', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('Julius', 'PERSON'),("'", 'O'),('wife', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('was', 'O'),('Ethel', 'PERSON'),('Sara', 'PERSON'),('Turing', 'PERSON'),('(', 'O'),('née', 'O'),('Stoney', 'O'),('1881–1976', 'O'),(')', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('daughter', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('Edward', 'PERSON'),('Waller', 'PERSON'),('Stoney', 'PERSON'),(',', 'O'),('chief', 'O'),('engineer', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('Madras', 'ORGANIZATION'),('Railways', 'ORGANIZATION'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 4:
===========
.......................................
('The', 'O'),('Stoneys', 'O'),('were', 'O'),('a', 'O'),('Protestant', 'O'),('Anglo-Irish', 'O'),('gentry', 'O'),('family', 'O'),('from', 'O'),('both', 'O'),('County', 'O'),('Tipperary', 'O'),('and', 'O'),('County', 'LOCATION'),('Longford', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('while', 'O'),('Ethel', 'PERSON'),('herself', 'O'),('had', 'O'),('spent', 'O'),('much', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('her', 'O'),('childhood', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('County', 'O'),('Clare', 'PERSON'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 5:
===========
.......................................
('Julius', 'PERSON'),("'", 'O'),('work', 'O'),('with', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('ICS', 'O'),('brought', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('family', 'O'),('to', 'O'),('British', 'O'),('India', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('where', 'O'),('his', 'O'),('grandfather', 'O'),('had', 'O'),('been', 'O'),('a', 'O'),('general', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('Bengal', 'ORGANIZATION'),('Army', 'ORGANIZATION'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 6:
===========
However, both Julius and Ethel wanted their children to be brought up in Britain, so they moved to Maida Vale, London, where Alan Turing was born on 23 June 1912, as recorded by a blue plaque on the outside of the house of his birth, later the Colonnade Hotel.
.......................................
('However', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('both', 'O'),('Julius', 'PERSON'),('and', 'O'),('Ethel', 'PERSON'),('wanted', 'O'),('their', 'O'),('children', 'O'),('to', 'O'),('be', 'O'),('brought', 'O'),('up', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('Britain', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('so', 'O'),('they', 'O'),('moved', 'O'),('to', 'O'),('Maida', 'LOCATION'),('Vale', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('London', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('where', 'O'),('Alan', 'PERSON'),('Turing', 'PERSON'),('was', 'O'),('born', 'O'),('on', 'O'),('23', 'O'),('June', 'O'),('1912', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('as', 'O'),('recorded', 'O'),('by', 'O'),('a', 'O'),('blue', 'O'),('plaque', 'O'),('on', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('outside', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('house', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('his', 'O'),('birth', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('later', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('Colonnade', 'LOCATION'),('Hotel', 'LOCATION'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 7:
===========
.......................................
('Turing', 'O'),('had', 'O'),('an', 'O'),('elder', 'O'),('brother', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('John', 'PERSON'),('(', 'PERSON'),('the', 'O'),('father', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('Sir', 'O'),('John', 'PERSON'),('Dermot', 'PERSON'),('Turing', 'PERSON'),(',', 'O'),('12th', 'O'),('Baronet', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('Turing', 'O'),('baronets', 'O'),(')', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 8:
===========
.......................................
('Turing', 'PERSON'),("'s", 'O'),('father', 'O'),("'s", 'O'),('civil', 'O'),('service', 'O'),('commission', 'O'),('was', 'O'),('still', 'O'),('active', 'O'),('and', 'O'),('during', 'O'),('Turing', 'PERSON'),("'s", 'O'),('childhood', 'O'),('years', 'O'),('Turing', 'O'),("'s", 'O'),('parents', 'O'),('travelled', 'O'),('between', 'O'),('Hastings', 'LOCATION'),('in', 'O'),('England', 'LOCATION'),('and', 'O'),('India', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('leaving', 'O'),('their', 'O'),('two', 'O'),('sons', 'O'),('to', 'O'),('stay', 'O'),('with', 'O'),('a', 'O'),('retired', 'O'),('Army', 'ORGANIZATION'),('couple', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 9:
===========
.......................................
('At', 'O'),('Hastings', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('Turing', 'PERSON'),('stayed', 'O'),('at', 'O'),('Baston', 'LOCATION'),('Lodge', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('Upper', 'LOCATION'),('Maze', 'LOCATION'),('Hill', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('St', 'LOCATION'),('Leonards-on-Sea', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('now', 'O'),('marked', 'O'),('with', 'O'),('a', 'O'),('blue', 'O'),('plaque', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 10:
===========
.......................................
('The', 'O'),('plaque', 'O'),('was', 'O'),('unveiled', 'O'),('on', 'O'),('23', 'O'),('June', 'O'),('2012', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('centenary', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('Turing', 'PERSON'),("'s", 'O'),('birth', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 11:
===========
Very early in life, Turing showed signs of the genius that he was later to display prominently.
.......................................
('Very', 'O'),('early', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('life', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('Turing', 'PERSON'),('showed', 'O'),('signs', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('genius', 'O'),('that', 'O'),('he', 'O'),('was', 'O'),('later', 'O'),('to', 'O'),('display', 'O'),('prominently', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 12:
===========
His parents purchased a house in Guildford in 1927, and Turing lived there during school holidays.
.......................................
('His', 'O'),('parents', 'O'),('purchased', 'O'),('a', 'O'),('house', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('Guildford', 'LOCATION'),('in', 'O'),('1927', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('and', 'O'),('Turing', 'PERSON'),('lived', 'O'),('there', 'O'),('during', 'O'),('school', 'O'),('holidays', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 13:
===========
The location is also marked with a blue plaque.
.......................................
('The', 'O'),('location', 'O'),('is', 'O'),('also', 'O'),('marked', 'O'),('with', 'O'),('a', 'O'),('blue', 'O'),('plaque', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 14:
===========
Turing's parents enrolled him at St Michael's, a day school at 20 Charles Road, St Leonards-on-Sea, at the age of six.
.......................................
('Turing', 'PERSON'),("'s", 'O'),('parents', 'O'),('enrolled', 'O'),('him', 'O'),('at', 'O'),('St', 'ORGANIZATION'),('Michael', 'ORGANIZATION'),("'s", 'O'),(',', 'O'),('a', 'O'),('day', 'O'),('school', 'O'),('at', 'O'),('20', 'O'),('Charles', 'LOCATION'),('Road', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('St', 'LOCATION'),('Leonards-on-Sea', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('at', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('age', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('six', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 15:
===========
The headmistress recognised his talent early on, as did many of his subsequent teachers.
.......................................
('The', 'O'),('headmistress', 'O'),('recognised', 'O'),('his', 'O'),('talent', 'O'),('early', 'O'),('on', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('as', 'O'),('did', 'O'),('many', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('his', 'O'),('subsequent', 'O'),('teachers', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 16:
===========
.......................................
('Between', 'O'),('January', 'O'),('1922', 'O'),('and', 'O'),('1926', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('Turing', 'PERSON'),('was', 'O'),('educated', 'O'),('at', 'O'),('Hazelhurst', 'ORGANIZATION'),('Preparatory', 'ORGANIZATION'),('School', 'ORGANIZATION'),(',', 'O'),('an', 'O'),('independent', 'O'),('school', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('village', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('Frant', 'LOCATION'),('in', 'O'),('Sussex', 'LOCATION'),('(', 'O'),('now', 'O'),('East', 'O'),('Sussex', 'O'),(')', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
.......................................
('In', 'O'),('1926', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('at', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('age', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('13', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('he', 'O'),('went', 'O'),('on', 'O'),('to', 'O'),('Sherborne', 'ORGANIZATION'),('School', 'ORGANIZATION'),(',', 'O'),('a', 'O'),('boarding', 'O'),('independent', 'O'),('school', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('market', 'O'),('town', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('Sherborne', 'LOCATION'),('in', 'O'),('Dorset', 'LOCATION'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 18:
===========
.......................................
('The', 'O'),('first', 'O'),('day', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('term', 'O'),('coincided', 'O'),('with', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('1926', 'O'),('General', 'O'),('Strike', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('Britain', 'LOCATION'),(',', 'O'),('but', 'O'),('he', 'O'),('was', 'O'),('so', 'O'),('determined', 'O'),('to', 'O'),('attend', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('that', 'O'),('he', 'O'),('rode', 'O'),('his', 'O'),('bicycle', 'O'),('unaccompanied', 'O'),('60', 'O'),('miles', 'O'),('(', 'O'),('97', 'O'),('km', 'O'),(')', 'O'),('from', 'O'),('Southampton', 'LOCATION'),('to', 'O'),('Sherborne', 'PERSON'),(',', 'O'),('stopping', 'O'),('overnight', 'O'),('at', 'O'),('an', 'O'),('inn', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 19:
===========
Turing's natural inclination towards mathematics and science did not earn him respect from some of the teachers at Sherborne, whose definition of education placed more emphasis on the classics.
.......................................
('Turing', 'O'),("'s", 'O'),('natural', 'O'),('inclination', 'O'),('towards', 'O'),('mathematics', 'O'),('and', 'O'),('science', 'O'),('did', 'O'),('not', 'O'),('earn', 'O'),('him', 'O'),('respect', 'O'),('from', 'O'),('some', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('teachers', 'O'),('at', 'O'),('Sherborne', 'ORGANIZATION'),(',', 'O'),('whose', 'O'),('definition', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('education', 'O'),('placed', 'O'),('more', 'O'),('emphasis', 'O'),('on', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('classics', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 20:
===========
His headmaster wrote to his parents: "I hope he will not fall between two stools.
.......................................
('His', 'O'),('headmaster', 'O'),('wrote', 'O'),('to', 'O'),('his', 'O'),('parents', 'O'),(':', 'O'),('``', 'O'),('I', 'O'),('hope', 'O'),('he', 'O'),('will', 'O'),('not', 'O'),('fall', 'O'),('between', 'O'),('two', 'O'),('stools', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 21:
===========
If he is to stay at public school, he must aim at becoming educated.
.......................................
('If', 'O'),('he', 'O'),('is', 'O'),('to', 'O'),('stay', 'O'),('at', 'O'),('public', 'O'),('school', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('he', 'O'),('must', 'O'),('aim', 'O'),('at', 'O'),('becoming', 'O'),('educated', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 22:
===========
If he is to be solely a Scientific Specialist, he is wasting his time at a public school".
.......................................
('If', 'O'),('he', 'O'),('is', 'O'),('to', 'O'),('be', 'O'),('solely', 'O'),('a', 'O'),('Scientific', 'O'),('Specialist', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('he', 'O'),('is', 'O'),('wasting', 'O'),('his', 'O'),('time', 'O'),('at', 'O'),('a', 'O'),('public', 'O'),('school', 'O'),("''", 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 23:
===========
.......................................
('Despite', 'O'),('this', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('Turing', 'PERSON'),('continued', 'O'),('to', 'O'),('show', 'O'),('remarkable', 'O'),('ability', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('the', 'O'),('studies', 'O'),('he', 'O'),('loved', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('solving', 'O'),('advanced', 'O'),('problems', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('1927', 'O'),('without', 'O'),('having', 'O'),('studied', 'O'),('even', 'O'),('elementary', 'O'),('calculus', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
Sentence 24:
===========
In 1928, aged 16, Turing encountered Albert Einstein's work; not only did he grasp it, but it is possible that he managed to deduce Einstein's questioning of Newton's laws of motion from a text in which this was never made explicit.
.......................................
('In', 'O'),('1928', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('aged', 'O'),('16', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('Turing', 'PERSON'),('encountered', 'O'),('Albert', 'PERSON'),('Einstein', 'PERSON'),("'s", 'O'),('work', 'O'),(';', 'O'),('not', 'O'),('only', 'O'),('did', 'O'),('he', 'O'),('grasp', 'O'),('it', 'O'),(',', 'O'),('but', 'O'),('it', 'O'),('is', 'O'),('possible', 'O'),('that', 'O'),('he', 'O'),('managed', 'O'),('to', 'O'),('deduce', 'O'),('Einstein', 'PERSON'),("'s", 'O'),('questioning', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('Newton', 'PERSON'),("'s", 'O'),('laws', 'O'),('of', 'O'),('motion', 'O'),('from', 'O'),('a', 'O'),('text', 'O'),('in', 'O'),('which', 'O'),('this', 'O'),('was', 'O'),('never', 'O'),('made', 'O'),('explicit', 'O'),('.', 'O')
_______________________________________
